GABRIELLE WALD

(617) 413-0253 • gabibmello@gmail.com • linkedin/gabriellewald • github/gabriellewald

SUMMARY

I am a Data Scientist interested in surfacing insights from data. I have experience creating accessible visualizations and predictive models for a wide range of applications. I'm passionate about the scientific method and the use of technology to generate positive impact, improve services, and uncover possible solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Data Science Fellow, Springboard School of Data

Aug 2020 - Present

550+ hours of hands-on coursework, with 1:1 industry expert mentorship

- Created predictive model to understand student performance in CA K-12 public schools
- Formulated and tested hypotheses to understand demographic factors in performance
- Found and transformed several files to construct unique datasets
- Used machine learning algorithms in classification and regression models

Data Science Fellow, DS4A Empowerment Program | Correlation One

Oct 2020 - Feb 2021

Merit-based fellowship with 5% acceptance rate led by Harvard Prof. Natesh Pillai

- Co-created capstone project to understand financial impact in CA K-12 public schools
- Ran regression models to determine variables of impact and identify confounding factors
- Performed t-test and chi-square analysis for hypothesis testing
- Conducted exploratory data analysis and created meaningful plots to identify patterns

Research Data Analyst, SELF-lab | UC Davis

May 2019 - Jul 2020

- · Ran descriptives and constructed visualization for research in collaboration with the World Bank
- Organized and cleaned data with over 63,000 data points in R / Excel to prepare data for analysis
- Collaborated with researchers and participated in planning meetings

Research Assistant, Oakes Lab | Center for Mind and Brain

Aug 2018 – Jul 2019

- Ran eye-tracking software SMI, collected and coded infant behavior data
- Screened participants and followed IRB guidelines for research projects
- Trained new RAs on lab procedures and collaborated with the research team

Research Assistant, Rivera Lab | Center for Mind and Brain

Aug 2017 – Oct 2018

- Carried out data collection for behavioral studies
- Administered eye-tracking to study subjects
- · Collaborated with P.I., PhD students, and fellow researchers

Vice President of Scholarship, PTK Honor Society International

Jan 2015 - Jan 2016

- Partnered with organizations for collaboration on campus projects
- Led weekly meetings with society members to address action items
- Organized and presented induction ceremony to welcome new inductees

EDUCATION

University of California Davis

2017 - 2020

- Bachelor of Science in Cognitive Science, Computer Science and Neuroscience emphasis, 3.65 GPA
- Relevant coursework: Applied Statistics, Biostatistics, Statistical Analysis in R, Linear Algebra, Research Methods, Data Structures and Algorithms in Python, Object Oriented Programming in Python

University of Hawaii | Kapiolani Community College

2013 - 2015

- Associate of Arts in Liberal Arts, Applied Linguistics Concentration 4.0 GPA Valedictorian
- Leadership: Vice President of Scholarship at Phi Theta Kappa Alpha Kappa Psi Chapter

PROJECTS

Passing the Standards Projection

May 2021

<u>GitHub</u> Predictive model to project the percentage of students passing standard tests in CA K-12 public schools. This project was an in-depth investigation of factors possibly affecting school performance.

- Modeled training data with several regression algorithms: linear regression, logistic regression, decision tree, random forest, lasso, and PCA
- Created unique dataset with test scores, financial investment in education, and several demographics regarding students and their families

SKILLS

- Programming: Python, numpy, pandas, matplotlib, sklearn, statsmodel, seaborn, jupyter notebook
- Descriptive and Inferential Statistics: p-value, test for significance (z-test, t-test, chi-squared, ANOVA)
- Experimental Design: A/B testing, hypothesis testing, confidence level
- Predictive Modeling: linear regression, logistic regression, classification, clustering, decision trees, random forest
- Data Science Methods: mining, wrangling, cleaning, analysis, visualization, storytelling
- Version Control: git, github
- Databases: SQL